Guide to the Nell Mondy papers, 1932-2005.
Mondy, Nell papers, 1932-2005
- III. Potato Research (Box 13)
  - Potato Association of America
    - 69th Annual Conference Physiological Section Boise Idaho, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - 71st Annual Conference St. Paul, Minnesota, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - 72nd Annual Conference Fort Collins, Colorado, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Nell Mondy abstract Fort Collins, Colorado, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - 83rd Annual Meeting New Jersey, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Physiological Section (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Potato News, 2000, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Potato News, 2001, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Potato News, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Honorary Life Members (Box 14, Folder 70)
  - International Potato Center (CIP)
    - Report, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 57)
    - Report, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 58)
    - Report 1992 (Box 13, Folder 59)
    - Report, 1995-1996 (Box 13, Folder 60)
    - Circular, 1981-1987 (Box 13, Folder 61)
    - International Potato Centre Report, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - International Potato Centre Report Lima Peru, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Peru
    - Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 62)
    - Correspondence and Receipts (Box 13, Folder 63)
  - Guatemala
    - Correspondence with Instituto de Nutricion de Centro America y Panama (Box 13, Folder 64)
  - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture (IITA)
    - Reports, 1996-1997 (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - Reports, 1990, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 66)
  - General Potato
    - Netherlands Potato Institute (Box 13, Folder 67)
    - Potato News, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 68)
    - Potato News, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 69)
    - Potato News, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 70)
    - Potato News, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 71)
    - Research Support for Empire State Potato Club, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 72)
    - Potato Program at Cornell (Box 13, Folder 73)
    - Potato Proteins (Box 13, Folder 74)
    - French Fry Potato Quality (Box 13, Folder 75)
    - Use of Plants for Toxicity Assessment (Box 13, Folder 76)
    - McClain Report, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 77)
    - International Food Security, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - National Potato Research and Education Foundation (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Bruise Free Potato Idaho Ext (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Potato Facts USDA, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - National Potato Council Speed Letter, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - USDA Food and Home Notes, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Factors affecting the qualities of potato (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Quality of potatoes in relation to chemical composition. Frontiers in Food Research speech (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Mondy Featured in Potato Growers, 1986-06 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Nell Mondy featured in Spudman, 1984-07 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Golden Nematode Resistant Varieties (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Examples of National Potato Council Statistical Yearbook, 1992, 1995, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Study of TYA Toxicity in Main, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - Reprints of Glyco work in Maine (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Potatoes take her to Scotland (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - CPIC: Prevent Sprouting (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Potato, Food and General Industry Letters, 1974-1992 (Box 14, Folder 75)
    - Photographs of Potatoes (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Nell Mondy's Involvement in Potato Research and Organizations
    - Research Citation-Science News (Box 14, Folder 55)
    - Research Citation-Health (Box 14, Folder 56)
    - Research Citation-Rodale's Gardening (Box 14, Folder 57)
    - Research Citation-Weight Watchers (Box 14, Folder 58)
    - Research Citation-Eating Well (Box 14, Folder 59)
    - Research Citation-National Geographic (Box 14, Folder 60)
    - Research Citation-Natural Health (Box 14, Folder 61)
    - Research Citation-Smithsonian (Box 14, Folder 62)
    - Research Citation-Country Life (Box 14, Folder 63)
    - Research Citation-Cornell Alum News (Box 14, Folder 64)
    - Research Citation-Cornell Focus (Box 14, Folder 65)
    - Research Citation-Potato Grower (Box 14, Folder 66)
    - Research Report-NY Food and Life Science Quality, Vol 4 no.1, Vol 19 no.3 (Box 14, Folder 67)
    - Research Report-University of Idaho Winter Commodity School, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 68)
    - Research Report Human Ecology Forum, Vol 3 no.1, 1972 (Box 14, Folder 69)
    - Role in Potato Association of America (Box 14, Folder 71)
    - Research on the Potato (Box 14, Folder 72)
    - Microscopic images of the Potato, 1970-1979 (Box 20, Folder 68-69)
    - Prof Recognition American Potato Journal, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 73)
    - Life Members Recognition American Potato Journal, 1983-09 (Box 14, Folder 74)
    - Research Laboratory Methods I (Box 14, Folder 76)
    - Research Laboratory Methods II (Box 14, Folder 77)
    - Honors in Agriculture (Box 14, Folder 78)
    - International Honors (Box 14, Folder 79)
  - Nell Mondy's Reflection on Potato Research
    - Mondy's Introduction to Potato Research (Box 13, Folder 78)
    - Mondy's Research and Lectures (Box 13, Folder 79)
  - National Potato Research Proposal, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - European Association for Potato Research, Switzerland (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - National Potato Research Proposal, 1986-1987 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Correspondence
    - Marketing Section
    - Funding
    - National Potato Research Proposal, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Early Bulletin on Potatoes, 1920-1939 (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - Early Bulletin on Potatoes, 1930-1939 (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - Early Bulletins on Potatoes (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - Laboratory Rules, Potato Research (Box 3, Folder 132)
- IV. Honors
  - Personalities of America (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - National ADP Institute- EPA (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - New York Academy of Science (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Nutrition Today Society (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Distinguished Alumna- Ouachita Baptist College (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Press/Letters- Distinguished Alumna Award (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Press/Letters- Distinguished Alumna Award Originals (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Ouachita-Student Years, 1939-1943 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Distinguished Alum Award, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Mondy-Provine Scholarship, 1966-2005 (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Birkett Williams Lecture, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - Ouachita at 100 (Centennial Advancement Campaign), 1982 (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Centennial Achievement Award, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Nell Mondy Lectureship, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Nell I. Mondy Chemistry Laboratory, Jones Science Center, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Citations-Ouachita Circle (Mondy-Food Science), 1998 (Box 15, Folder 48)
  - Who's Who in American Colleges and Universities, 1941-1943 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Press- Who's Who (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Who's Who in Arkansas, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Social Directory, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Certificates:
    - Kiwanis Club of Ithaca (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Pesticide Residue Analysis Workshop (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - A G-Domecon Council (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Summer Institute on Educational Media (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Society for Cryobiology (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - The American Dietetic Association (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Fritzsche Brothers, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Personalities of America, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Nutrition Today Society, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - ADP, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Cornell Summer Institute on Educational Media, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Pesticide Residue Analysis Workshop, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - AG - Domecon Council, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Fritzsche Brothers, Inc., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - American Dietetic Association, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Society of Cryobiology, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Honor Society Certificates (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Iota Sigma Pi, 1944 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Sigma Delta Eplison, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Pi Lambda Theta, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - Phi Kappa Phi, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Omicron Nu, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Phi Tau Sigma, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Sigma Xi, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Gamma Sigma Delta, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Honor Societies:
    - Sigma Delta Epsilon- Honors in Physical Science (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Gamma Sigma Delta- Honors in Agriculture (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Pi Lambda Theta- Honors in Education (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Sigma Xi- Honors in Scientific Research (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Omicron Nu- Honors in Home Economics (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Phi Kappa Phi- General Honorary (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Iota Sigma Pi- Honors in Chemistry (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Phi Tau Sigma- Honorary in Food Science (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Texas Iota Sigma Pi, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Omicron Nu (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Phi Kappa Phi, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Pi Lambda Theta (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Sigma Xi, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Food Science Honorary Phi Tau Sigma (charter member), 1954 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Gamma Sigma Delta, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Certificates from various Honor Societies and Workshops Attended, 1950-1979 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Iota Sigma Pi, 1944 (Box 15, Folder 93)
    - Sigma Delta Epsilon, 1946 (Box 15, Folder 94)
    - Omicron Nu, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 95)
    - Pi Lambda Theta, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 96)
    - Phi Kappa Phi, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 97)
    - Phi Tau Sigma Honorary Society Charter Member, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 98)
    - Sigma Xi, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 99)
    - Honor Society Of Agriculture Gamma Sigma Delta, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 100)
  - Honorary Life Memberships:
    - Potato Association, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - GWIS, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - PAA Honorary Life, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - GWIS Honorary Life, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Potato Association of America (Honorary Life), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Graduate Women in Science (Honorary Life), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Fellowships
    - Elected Fellow in: (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Institute of Chemists
      - AAAS- American Association for Advancement in Science
      - IFT- Institute of Food Technologists
    - Cornell Sigma Xi Fellowship (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Sigma Xi Fellowship, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - American Institute of Chemists Fellow, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - AAAS Fellow, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - IFT Fellow, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Sigma Xi (Fellowship), 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Fellow American Institute of Chemists (Fellow), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Institute of Food Technologist (Fellow), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - American Association for Advancement in Science (Fellow), 1982 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Letters- IFT Fellow (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Early Awards
    - Who's Who among students in American Universities and Colleges, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Who's Who among students in American Universities and Colleges, 1942-1943
    - 1952-1953 Cornell Sigma Xi Fellowship
    - Danforth Award - Seminar on Creative Teaching, 1954
    - Research Featured in RESEARCH AT CORNELL, 1959
    - National Science Foundation Award, University Teachers of Chemistry, 1959
    - Summer Institute for College Teachers of Chemistry - Indiana University, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - NATO Advance Study Institute, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Ouachita Centennial, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Distinguished Alumna, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - H.S. Centennial Award, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Nutrition Today Society, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Personalities of America, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - National President of GWIS, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - National Women's Hall of Fame, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Honors and Awards, 1997
    - IFT Award (Box 5, Folder 81)
    - IFT Congratulation Letter (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Nell Mondy Organic Chemistry Laboratory Dedication, Ouachita Baptist University - Arkedelphia, Arkansas (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Mondy-Carroll Lectureship, William Baptist College - Walnut Ridge, Arizona (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Honors in Agriculture, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 117)
  - Miscellaneous Other Honors, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 118)
  - Sharing Food Chemistry Teaching Method at Alma Mater (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Sharing Food Chem. Teaching Method at Alma Mater (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Research Request (Japan), 1970 (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - IFT Paper Selected (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - IFT Award, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - Early Awards (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Ouachita Distinguish Alumna, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Centennial Achievement Award Ouchita Centennial, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - High School Centennial Award, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Class Captain - Science Enrichment Award, Centennial Achievement Award, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - Who's Who in Arkansas, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - Listed as Outstanding Intellectual of the 21st Century by the International Biographical Center (IBC), 2000 (Box 12, Folder 85)
  - Nomination as Intellectual of the Year IBC, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 86)
  - 21st Century Award for Achievement IBC, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 87)
  - Invited to become Fellow of American Biographical Institute (ABI), 2001 (Box 12, Folder 88)
  - Nomination for Woman of the Year by ABI (Box 12, Folder 89)
  - National Women's Hall of Fame, 1993-2002 (Box 12, Folder 90)
  - National Women's Hall of Fame Invitation to Induction Ceremony, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 91)
  - Graduate Women in Science- National Meritorious Service Award (Box 12, Folder 92)
  - National Women's History Museum (Charter member), 2002-02-12 (Box 12, Folder 93)
  - Chosen to Review Manuscript for Food Control published by Elsevier Science Ltd, Oxford, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 94)
  - Wall of Tolerance - Name placed on the Wall, 2002-11 (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - 9th edition American Men of Science, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - National Women's Hall of Fame, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - National Women's History Museum- Charter Member, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - N. Mondy Chem Lab. Women Hall of Fame Plaque, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Publication of Mondy AutoBiography- Dorrance Publishing, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Reminiscences-Texas University, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Tompkins County: Landlords Association of Tompkins County Newsletter, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Tompkins County: Certificate of Appreciation, Tompkins County Center for Crime Victims, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - 12th World Congress of Food Science. National Press, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Pocahontas Star Herald Honors Mondy, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Who's Who in Agriculture Higher Education, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Book- 'You Never Fail Until You Stop Trying: Story of a Pioneer Woman Chemist, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 89)
  - Book Press, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 90)
  - Book Clippings, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 91)
  - Fellow American Institute of Chemists (AIC), 1968 (Box 15, Folder 109)
  - Fellow American Association of the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1982 (Box 15, Folder 110)
  - International Platform Association (IPA), 1978 (Box 15, Folder 112)
  - IPA-History (Box 15, Folder 113)
  - IPA-Meetings (Box 15, Folder 114)
  - IPA-Publicist (Box 15, Folder 115)
  - INT Congress: NATO Seminar-Recent Advances in Food Science - Scotland, 1960 (Box 15, Folder 120)
  - INT Congress: 12th International Congress in Food Science - USA, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 121)
  - Tompkins County Criminal Justice Advisory Board (Box 15, Folder 122)
  - Domecon, Elected Faculty Advisor, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 123)
  - Professional Skills Roster at Cornell University (Box 15, Folder 127)
  - History, 1967-1982 (Box 15, Folder 127)
  - Nell's Christmas Letters, 1966-2004 (Box 15, Folder 128)
  - Idaho Potato Book, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 129)
  - High School
    - Pocahontas High School-Graduation Award, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - PHS-Reunions (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Centennial Achievement Award, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Pocahontas Star Herald: Clippings, 1978-1979 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Williams Baptist College
    - Gift to Williams Baptist College, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Williams Baptist College, Chemistry Laboratory, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 49)
    - Nell Mondy Scholarship, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Mondy-Carroll Lecture, Blooomer, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Mondy-Carroll Lectureship Speakers, 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Williams Baptist College - Mondy-Carroll Lectureship, 1990-1999 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Cornell University
    - Speech to "Expand Your Horizons", 2004 (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - College of Agriculture and Life Sciences Outstanding Alumni Award Certificate (CALS), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 66)
    - Nomination (CALS), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 67)
    - Correspondence (CALS), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 68)
    - Banquet (CALS), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 69)
    - Press (CALS), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 70)
    - Clippings (CALS), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 71)
    - Letters Congratulatory (CALS), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 72)
    - Poster in Kennedy Hall, 2000-2001 (Box 15, Folder 73)
    - Photos (Box 15, Folder 74)
    - Mann Library Campaign Committee (Box 15, Folder 75)
    - Nell I. Mondy Reading Room (Library), 2000 (Box 15, Folder 76)
    - Dedication Photographs (Library) (Box 15, Folder 77)
    - Book Plate: Plain Words About Food (Library) (Box 15, Folder 78)
    - Liberty Hyde Bailey-Certificate (Box 15, Folder 79)
    - Liberty Hyde Bailey Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 80)
    - Liberty Hyde Bailey Banquet (Box 15, Folder 81)
    - Inaugural Member, Liberty Hyde Bailey Leadership Society (Box 15, Folder 82)
    - College of Human Ecology-Luncheon (Box 15, Folder 83)
    - College of Human Ecology-Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 84)
    - College of Human Ecology-Press Poem (Box 15, Folder 85)
    - College of Human Ecology-Clippings (Box 15, Folder 86)
    - College of Human Ecology-Photo (Box 15, Folder 87)
    - College of Human Ecology-Poem, Laboratory (Box 15, Folder 88)
    - College of Human Ecology- Lab of Human Performance Dedication, 2003 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - International Biographical Centre (IBC)
    - International Biographical Centre: Congress on Arts and Communication, 1979 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - The 20th Century Award for Achievement, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - 2000 Outstanding Scientists of the 20th Century, 2nd Edition, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Outstanding Intellectuals of the 21st Century, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Outstanding Intellectuals of the 20th Century, 2000
    - Who's Who in 21st Century, 1st Edition, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Woman of the Year, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Worldwide Honors List, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - World Peace and Diplomacy Forum, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Dictionary of International Biography, 30th Edition, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Worldwide Honors List, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - 2000 Outstanding Intellectuals of 21st Century, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Lifetime Achievement Award, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Dictionary of International Biography, 31st Edition, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Nomination International Professional of the Year, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Graduate Women in Science
    - National Award of Recognition, Human Ecology News, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Graduate Women in Science Honors, 1946, 1986, 1996, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 92)
  - American Biographical Institute (ABI)
    - American Biographical Institute Hall of Fame, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - American Medal of Honor, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Outstanding Woman of the Year, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - World Lifetime Achievement Award, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Woman of the Year Awards, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - 2003 Edition American Biography (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Nomination, International Peace Prize, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Potato Association of America (PAA)
    - Citations April, July (missing), 2003 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Potato Association of America-Certificate, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Potato Journal, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - Banquet, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - News, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - Congratulatory Letter: Potato Association of America, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - 75th Annual Honors to Honorary Life Members, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - Photos: Honorary Life Member, East Lansing, Michigan, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - National Potato Research Proposal (marketing section), 1992 (Box 15, Folder 60)
  - Institute of Foods and Technologies (IFT)
    - Institute of Food Technologies: Nomination Elizabeth Flemming Steir Award, Orlando, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 61)
    - Clippings, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 62)
    - Letter from IFT Friends, Cornell Dean, etc., 1997 (Box 15, Folder 63)
    - Letters from students, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 64)
    - 50 Year National Member: IFT pin award, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - Fellow Institute of Food Technologies, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 111)
  - Foreign Countries
    - Ivory Coast-African Regional Seminar: Delegate, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 101)
    - Ivory Coast-List of Participants, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 102)
    - Ivory Coast-Working Groups, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 103)
    - Ivory Coast-Nell's Speech, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 104)
    - Ivory Coast-Technical Report, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 105)
    - Ivory Coast-Proceedings, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 106)
    - Ivory Coast-Third World Organization for Woman, 1984 (Box 15, Folder 107)
    - Ivory Coast-Reflections on Africa (Box 15, Folder 108)
    - Mauritius-Speech: Special Invitation (Box 15, Folder 116)
    - Mauritius Experience (Box 15, Folder 117)
    - Mauritius-Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 118)
    - Mauritius-History (Box 15, Folder 119)
    - India-Government Arrangements, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 124)
    - India-Documents from Potato Institute, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 125)
    - India-Documents from Dairy Institute in Karma, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 126)
    - Indonesia-Development Project, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 130)
    - Indonesia-Correspondence, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 131)
    - Indonesia-Nell Mondy Report, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 132)
    - Indonesia Clippings, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 133)
    - Indonesia-Speech by Dr. Mondy, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    - Book from Indonesia: Food Technology and Nutrition- Gadjah Mada University, Handbook for Service at Gadjah Mada University, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Mainland China-IFT China Delegation, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 136)
    - China-Correspondence, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - China-Report on Trip, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - China-Some Publications of Universities Visited, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 139)
- V. Associations/Institutes (Box 7)
  - Graduate Women in Science (GWIS)
    - Early History, 1921-1972, 1972-1978 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - R. Dickie History, 1979-1986 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Elizabeth O Hern History, 1986-1996 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - San Diego State University, San Diego, CA, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Chestnut Hill College, Philadelphia, PA, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Ithaca College, Ithaca, New York, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Hamlin University, St. Paul, MN, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Book Cadillac Hotel, Detroit MI, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Sheraton Centre, New York, New York, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Westin Bonaventure, Los Angeles, CA, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - International House, Philadelphia, PA, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Macalester College, St. Paul, MN, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - University of Tennessee, Chattanooga, TN, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - University of San Diego, San Diego, CA, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 14)